Hello! And welcome to this ensemble methods section.
大家好 欢迎来到集成方法这个版块
In this section, we'll learn how to take a bunch of
在这个版块中 我们将学习如何使用各种模型
models and join them together to get a better model.
以及如何连接它们 以得到一个更好的模型
We'll learn two of the most popular ensemble methods,
我们将学习两种最普遍的集成方法
namely bagging and boosting.
分别是 bagging 和 boosting
Actually, bagging has nothing to do with a bag.
bagging 和包包没有任何关系
It's short for bootstrap aggregating.
它指的是自助聚集
So here's the premise, let's say we have to take a test,
具体来说 假如我们要做一个测试
a true-false test for simplicity.
简单起见 假设我们要做判断题测试
And we're not feeling super comfortable for this test,
而我们不是很有信心
we want a little help from our friends.
所以需要向朋友求助
So here are our friends.
这就是我们的朋友们
In the first method, bagging,
如果用第一种方法 bagging
what we'll do is the following.
我们要做的事情是
We'll get each of our friends to answer the test separately,
让每个朋友分别做这项测试
and now at the end, we combine them.
最后把结果集成到一起
How do we combine them? There are many ways.
要怎么把结果集成到一起呢？方法有许多种
For example, if the answers on the tests are values,
例如 如果问题的答案与数值有关
we could average their answers.
那我们可以取平均值
Since they are yes-no questions, let's consider voting.
既然这个测试都是判断题 那么我们可以用计票的方式
So for each question,
对于每个问题
we will check which option got more answers from our friends,
我们看是 与 否 两个选项的得票数孰多孰少
and we'll answer that.
我们就选择得票多的答案
Thus, we combine our friends into
这样 我们就把朋友们集合成了一个天才
some genius friend that hopefully will do better on the test.
好帮助我们在测试中更好地表现
Now boosting is similar,
boosting 也是一样
except it just tries harder to exploit our friends strengths.
只是它会更进一步地汲取朋友们的智慧
So let's say we pick our first friend and he answers a test.
我们假设先选了一位朋友 让他来做测试
Now let's say this friend is a philosopher,
这位朋友是个哲学家
so he answered all the philosophy questions correctly,
所以 他答对了所有关于哲学的问题
but didn't answer the science ones very well.
但是关于科学的问题 他的表现并不好
So we pick among our friends to see who can help,
所以我们再考虑其他朋友 看谁能在这方面帮上忙
and surprise, we have a scientist friend.
然后我们惊喜地发现 朋友中有一个科学家
So we get her to answer the test and focus on the science questions.
所以再让她来做这项测试 然后重点关注科学问题
Now let's say she knows nothing about sports,
假设她对运动一无所知
and neither do our first friend.
那位哲学家朋友也不了解运动
So we see that those questions are all wrong.
所以他们关于运动的问题都答错了
So we get our friend who knows about sports to answer these questions,
然后我们再找擅长运动的朋友来回答这些问题
and then keep doing that with our math friend,
同样的道理 我们再找擅长数学的朋友
our musician friend, et cetera.
音乐家朋友 等等
At the end, we have combined them into
最后 我们把他们集合到一起
a super smart friend who does very well in the exam.
形成一个答题非常厉害的智慧群体
This method is called boosting.
这种方法就叫做 boosting
And here's some notation.
我们用下面的概念来表述一下
In this section, we'll call our friends the weak learners,
把我们的朋友称作 “弱学习器”
and the resulting smart friend, the strong learner.
把他们集合成的小群体称作 “强学习器”
These weak learners are not necessarily weak,
这些所谓的 “弱学习器” 并不是真的能力弱
but we simply denote them as such because we're joining them to create a stronger one.
我们只是这样描述 因为我们要集合形成一个相对更强的 “强学习器”
And in general, this is what we we'll do.
一般而言 这就是我们要做的事情
We have a bunch of models and we put them together to form a better model.
我们有一堆模型 然后把它们整合成一个更好的模型
And these models don't necessarily need to be very good.
所以 原模型不一定非要是很棒的模型
As a matter of fact, all we need is that they do just slightly better than random chance.
我们只需要它们的性能比随机选择的效能略好就够了